ZiMuZu.tv
字幕组
Acknowledge when in position, Sergeant Davis.
就位后请答复  戴维斯中士
Dagger team 1, copy. I keep losing you.
D组1队已收到  信号一直不好
How long till my backup's here?
增援什么时候到达
Working on it. Stand by.
正在查询  请待命
Say eight to ten minutes. Advise you stay put.
八至十分钟后到达  建议你留在原地
I can't wait for backup.
我等不及了
Send them in behind me.
让他们随后进来
Davis, maintain your position. They're on their way.
戴维斯  留在原地  他们正在赶来
Dagger team 1, are you seeing this?
这里是D组1队  你们看到了吗
There's some kind of disturbance here.
这里有东西在干扰信号
Davis, what is that? What are you seeing?
戴维斯  什么东西  你看到什么了
What the hell?
见鬼
Davis.
戴维斯
Davis, what's your status?
戴维斯  汇报情况
Davis, come in!
戴维斯  请回话
Got you.
找到你了
Gonna get a late start.
可能会推迟
Right, well, it's a closed session.
这是一次秘密会议
Most of the specs stayed the same...
规则大部分都没变...
Dr. Osbourne, call 204. Dr. Osbourne, call 204.
奥斯本博士请致电204室
They're issuing temporaries for that R and D, as far as I know.
据我所知  他们正为那项研发申请临时许可
Is that part of the same BADGE or...?
这也是基地防空地面警备系统的一部分吗
Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
肯定是
- All right. - How's it going?
-好吧  -进行得怎样了
- We'll get everything. - Marty was already in?
-我们会成功的  -马蒂已经到了吗
- Yeah. - And she's working on that project?
-是的  -她还在做那个项目吗
They'll be done in about a week. I was gonna say...
他们大概一周内能完成  我想说...
Don Taylor, report to laser laboratory building B, laser lab.
唐·泰勒  请到B栋激光实验室报到
Okay, I'll take a look.
我会看一下的
- Where have you been? - Solving problems.
-你去哪了  -解决点问题
You look... dusty.
你身上都是灰
Sometimes you gotta get dusty, Efrem.
有时候脏点是无法避免的  埃弗雷姆
- Test the pulse? - Yeah.
-要检测脉冲吗  -是的
Went down to the vault, asked Johnson for some tetracene,
我去地下室问约翰逊要点并四苯来着
but apparently, we don't store it.
但貌似我们并没有库存
It's outdated and expensive as shit.
那东西都过时了  而且还贵得要命
It got expensive. Back in the '90s, it used to be cheap.
只是后来贵了  九十年代的时候很便宜
So, if you look hard enough...
所以如果认真找找的话...
You can still find some lying around.
还是能找到些的
You find a street gang that slings tetracene?
你找街头匪帮要到了并四苯吗
Industrial printer cartridge, $14.99 back in the day.
工业打印机墨盒  当年也就14.99美元
- Get me a mount, would you? - Here, here you go.
-能给我个支架吗  -给你
Thank you.
谢谢
You gonna tell the suits
你要和上头说
you're running this on a 20-year-old part, right?
你在用二十年前的零部件运行它吗
I'll show them it works and I'm gonna tell them:
我会证明其可行  然后和他们说
"That's the difference between
"这就是原型机与
a prototype and a production model."
量产型号的区别
Okay.
好了
Concavity is spun to zero.
凹度调整为零
Lens track is hot.
启动镜面追踪
Alignment is keyed in.
进行直线校准
You are good to go.
可以开始了
I'll let you call it.
你来启动吧
If you think about the applications on other materials,
如果将其应用于其他材料
it could be fairly significant.
效果会相当明显
Metals, for instance,
比如说  金属制品
can be shattered with very little effort or noise.
受微小的力或噪音干扰就会被粉碎
Concrete, rubber...
混凝土  橡胶...
they're all vulnerable to violent temperature changes.
在巨大的温差下也会异常脆弱
Yeah, this project started as a request from Seal Team 6.
这个项目是应海豹突击六队之需而启动的
After the siege in Rwanda,
自卢旺达的围城以后
they came to us asking for the capability to
他们就来问我们能否
flash freeze or boil the enemy's water supply.
瞬间冻结或汽化敌人的水源
Now, this device could have driven the enemy out.
如今这个装置可以将敌人们赶出来了
And you... tried this on living things?
你有在活体上测试过吗
That wasn't our intent here, initially.
这不是我们的初衷
We'd like you test it.
希望你们能测试一下
Any volunteers?
有自愿的吗
Well... we'll give it a try.
我们会试试的
Gentlemen, why don't we go have a sit down?
先生们  大家先坐下来
We'll talk over the next steps. All right?
我们谈谈下一步安排  好吗
Yeah. Right this way.
这边走
What do you want, a clean conscience?
你是想良心无愧吗
Test it with a slab of beef for all I care.
就算用块牛肉来测试它  我也不在乎
What I want is to use it for what we originally designed it as.
我只希望不要背离了我们的设计初衷
A deterrent.
用于震慑
Nobody said anything about microwaving people's lungs.
没人说过要用来微波加热别人的肺
It's war.
这是战争
It's the business we're in.
是我们赖以为生的产业
Remember what you sold it to me as when you hired me?
你记得当初雇用我时说的套话吗
Defense.
致力于防御
And that's still partially true.
还是有部分属实的
But war is good business.
但战争是桩好生意
So is human trafficking.
人口贩卖也算
We work for DARPA, Mark.
马克  我们效力于国防高级研究计划局
We work for the government.
效力于政府
"I don't know what weapons we'll use to fight in World War III,
"我不知道第三次世界大战会用什么武器
but World War IV will be fought with..."
但第四次世界大战会用..."
"Sticks and stones." said Albert Einstein.
"木棍和石块"  爱因斯坦如是说
- He worked for the government. - That's right.
-他也为政府工作  -没错
And if you ask him, I don't think
如果你去问他
he thought that was his finest hour.
我想他不会觉得那是他最辉煌的时刻
I'm sure he has feelings about flash-boiling human flesh.
他肯定也会对把活人瞬间烧糊有意见的
Ever think about prosthetic limbs with full sensory feedback?
想过要研究有全感知反馈的义肢吗
Prosthetics... don't win wars.
研究义肢无助于打胜仗
Did you hear that?
你听到了吗
That is the empathetic scientist in you dying.
那是你逐渐失去的作为科学家的同情心
Did you brief your guys on how to operate the ray?
你和伙计们说了怎么操控射线了吗
- I did. - Good.
-说了  -很好
Then you can start packing.
那你可以开始收拾行李了
Can you be more specific?
能说具体点吗
About these goggles here.
是关于这些护目镜的
Your... hyperspectral goggles being deployed by
你的超光谱护目镜已装备给东欧
special forces in eastern Europe in the Moldovan war.
摩尔多瓦战役中的特种部队
I'm aware. I read the field reports.
早知道了  我看了现场报告
No, you have not read this report.
不  你还没看这份报告
Orland called me personally. General Orland.
奥伦德亲自打电话给我  奥伦德将军
He said things are very... sensitive down there.
他说那边的情况有点敏感
And they're... seeing things.
他们见到了些东西
Okay. Like what?
什么东西
They won't tell me.
他们不愿意告诉我
They won't share the video feed.
他们不愿意分享影像内容
They won't discuss what they're seeing.
也不愿意讨论所见之物
They just want the lead engineer
他们只想让首席工程师过去
down there to advise and consult.
提供建议和咨询
Look, you invented these goggles to keep our guys safe.
你发明这些护目镜是为了保护我们的人
Well, now they need your help.
而如今  他们需要你的帮助
Think of it as defense.
当作是为了防御吧
Let me reboot the guidance system.
让我来重启制导系统
It's locked tight. We have to pull it out.
锁得很死  我们要把它拉出来
All right, let's go. Move it out.
好了  走吧  移走它
- Mark Clyne? - What?
-马克·克莱恩  -什么
You the guy that designed the helmet cam?
是你设计的头盔摄像机吗
Yes. Mark clyne.
是的  马克·克莱恩
James Orland. Come with me.
我是詹姆斯·奥伦德  跟我来
A lot of new boots on the ground here.
这里又来了很多新士兵
The country's in chaos.
这个国家一团糟
The insurgency is mostly remnants of the military dictatorship
叛军主要是由军事独裁者余党组成的
that ran this place until about two months ago.
直到两个月前他们还控制着该地区
And their popular support
起初  在国家的北部地区
is primarily in the north part of the country,
俄罗斯边境附近
near the Russian border, and here in the capital.
和首都这里  他们都拥有广泛支持
The problem is their forces are well-trained.
问题在于他们的军队都训练有素
They're threatening to turn this whole thing into a civil war.
他们威胁要把局势发展成全面内战
Moldova. Russians had it, lost it.
俄罗斯曾统治摩尔多瓦  后又失去控制
It became independent, but it's struggling internally.
国家独立了  但内部纷争不断
On the one hand, you have an insurgency,
一方面  是叛军作乱
made up of the regime's former elite soldiers.
全都是政府的前精锐部队
They're well-trained and dangerous.
他们全都训练有素且极度危险
On the other, you have most of the population,
另一方面  这里的大部分国民
who are tearing down the regime's flags
都想推翻政府的统治
and demanding a new government.
渴望新政府
Civil unrest, as complicated as it is,
不管有多复杂
is a business we're familiar with.
内乱是我们所熟悉的事情
We like to think we're good at it.
我们觉得自己擅长处理内乱
But this thing your camera found...
但是你的摄像机发现的这个...
It's a whole new piece of business.
是种全新的玩意儿
I can't send this video to EUCOM.
我没法把这个视频交给美军欧洲司令部
I'm just afraid they'd think it's a joke.
我只是担心他们会认为这是个玩笑
DOD doesn't have a sense of humor.
国防部没有幽默感
Typically not. Hook us up.
通常没有  帮我们装好
I'm sure there's a scientific explanation for what's on these,
我相信这些东西有科学的解释
but until you tell me,
但是在你告诉我之前
I'm not sending it up the chain of command.
我是不会把它上交指挥系统的
- You done? - Yes, sir.
-搞定了  -是的  长官
- Get out. Seal us in. Wait outside. - Sir.
-出去把我们锁好  在外面等着  -是
Nobody here has been able to make heads or tails of this.
这里没有人对这个有任何头绪
It's thrown a wrench into our entire operation
由于一些我无法随意告知你的原因
for reasons I'm not at liberty to discuss with you.
我们的整个行动都被搅乱了
I can tell you we need answers fast.
我只能告诉你我们急需解释
- Do you mind? - You spotted that quick.
-介意我来吗  -你这么快就看到了
Five different helmet cams
五个头盔摄像机
picked up something similar in the last three weeks.
在过去三周内拍到了相似的东西
At first, our signals
最初情报技术人员
intelligence tech wrote it off as interference.
认为那是干扰信号
That's not interference.
那可不是干扰信号
I don't think you'd fly me all the way here
我觉得要是干扰信号的话
for interference.
不会让我大老远飞到这里来
Wanna tell me what you're thinking?
想跟我说说你的想法吗
I want you to tell me what you're thinking.
我想让你先说出你的想法
I don't know what I'm thinking... yet.
我...暂时没什么想法
But there is an explanation.
但这总是有解释的
That was the first sighting. Three others just like it.
这是第一次观测到的画面  另外三次类似
The last was different.
最后一次有些不同
It involved a member of Delta Force,
因为牵扯到一位三角洲部队成员
that makes it particularly sensitive.
这让事情变得极其敏感
This is Fran Madison with CIA.
这位是中情局的弗兰·麦迪逊
What special ops does here is done under CIA covert operations.
这里的特别行动都是中情局的秘密任务
You need to sign this before we go any further.
在我们继续之前你得把这个签了
- What is this? - It's an SCI oath.
-这是什么  -敏感信息保证书
You're acknowledging it's life
如果你泄露了
in prison if you reveal anything you're told.
告诉你的任何事  你将被判终身监禁
- Cue up the Davis file, please. - Yes, ma'am.
-找到戴维斯的文件  -是  长官
Three days ago we conducted a raid in mid-city.
三天前我们中城区进行了一次突击行动
Our communications were intermittent,
我们的通讯时断时续
and a guy got separated from the group...
有一位队员与队伍失联了
Where he ended up killed in action.
最终他在行动中被杀
He got closer than anybody.
他比任何人离得都近
Too close.
太近了
Dagger team 1, you seeing this?
这里是D组1队  你们看到了吗
There's some kind of disturbance here.
这里有东西在干扰信号
Davis, what is that? What are you seeing?
戴维斯  什么东西  你看到什么了
What the hell?
见鬼
Sergeant Chris Davis.
克里斯·戴维斯中士
Three-tour combat vet. Best of the best.
经历过三次战争的老兵  精英中的精英
In the last few weeks we've been finding bodies around the city
最近几周我们在全城范围内都发现了
that were killed in the same way.
死法相同的尸体
The autopsies defied all explanation.
尸检无法得出结论
Their internal organs were frozen
他们的内脏被冰冻住
and yet, their skin was burned and corroded.
然而皮肤却被烧灼和腐蚀了
The only response from the allied
从摩尔多瓦友军方面
Moldovan military contact is shock, confusion.
得到的唯一回应  只有震惊和困惑
And there's anger.
还有愤怒
There's teenagers
有一些少年
spray-painting "Genocide Aratare" at kill sites.
在出事地点喷涂"灭绝幽魂"的记号
- Genocide...? - "Aratare."
-灭绝什么  -"幽魂"
It's a local myth. The ghosts of war.
当地的传说  战争的鬼魂
"As nightmarish as." That's the literal translation.
"如同噩梦一般"  大概是这个意思
- That's very poetic. - Well, they're superstitious.
-还很有诗意  -那是他们的迷信
They somehow think...
他们不知怎地认为...
the horrors of the war have kicked up something unnatural.
战争的恐怖唤醒了一些非自然的力量
- We hope you have an alternate theory. - What do you think?
-我们希望你能给出别的理论  -你怎么看
Think you need a new name for them.
我认为你们得给它们起个新名字
Beyond that.
除了这个
Give me a copy of the data, some time...
给我一份这些数据的拷贝  给我点时间
That's not possible.
不可能
You want me to figure this out right now?
你们想让我现在就搞清楚
- We want your assessment. - I don't have one yet.
-我们需要你的看法  -我还没什么看法
Then, I think we have to send our working theory
那么  我们就得把目前的理论
up the chain of command.
上交给指挥系统
I don't wanna do that.
我不想这样做
Okay. What is your working theory?
好吧  目前的理论是什么
The agency thinks this is some kind of cloaking technology.
我们认为这是一种隐身技术
Insurgent soldiers wearing active camouflage.
叛军士兵穿着动态伪装服
In this country? Something that advanced?
在这个国家吗  那么先进的技术
CIA knows a few groups in Europe
中情局知道欧洲和亚洲的
and Asia could be working on active camouflage.
一些组织可能在研究动态伪装服
DARPA's worked on cloaking technology.
国防部高级研究计划局也在研究隐形技术
We're years away from a prototype.
我们离原型都还差好多年
Maybe somebody beat you to it.
也许有人领先了你们
DARPA is the leader in the field.
我们已经是这个领域最先进的了
Are you certain of that?
你确定吗
The regime spent heavily on weapons research.
地方政府斥巨资进行武器研究
Corruption, loose legislation.
腐败  松散的法治
You're a military lab and want obscurity?
对一个想要低调的军事实验室来说
- This is a great place to work and hide. - Okay.
-这里是悄悄进行研究的完美地点  -好吧
Let's say it is cloaking technology.
我们假设这是一种隐身技术
How do you account for cause of death?
怎么解释死因
A shock delivered to the victim.
对受害者的冲击波
I think you're reaching.
我觉得你只是瞎猜的
Our business requires us to make suppositions.
我们的工作需要进行推测
My business requires us to prove them.
而我的工作需要去证实这些推测
Your technician's job is to find glitches,
你们的技术人员的工作是找到故障
so, he sees glitches.
所以他们看到了故障
Your job is to find the enemy,
你们的工作是找到敌人
so, you see the enemy.
所以你们看到了敌人
Locals believe in spirits, so they see spirits.
本地人相信鬼魂  他们就看到了鬼魂
Everyone is biased, in one way or another.
在某一方面  每个人都有自己的偏见
So, my answer to you right
所以  现在我的回答是
now is that we lack data to support any theory.
我们目前缺少数据来支持任何理论
Okay.
好吧
What do you need to make a more definitive statement?
你需要什么来得出更肯定的结论
First, you need a better shot.
首先  你们得有更好的画面
That's what I'm looking for, a better shot.
这正是我想要的  更好的画面
How?
怎么做
- Right here, sir. - That's it.
-这边  长官  -就是这个
I brought this from DARPA. A hyperspectral camera.
我从DARPA带来了这个  超光谱摄像机
A more powerful version of the helmet cams your guys are using.
比你们用的头盔摄像机更强大的设备
It sees deeper into the spectrum of light.
它能看到深层次的光谱
Visible or invisible, if something's there,
不管是否可见  只要有东西
this'll pick it up.
它就能观察到
Can you mount this thing... on a delta vehicle?
你能把这东西安在三角洲部队的战车上吗
- I don't see why not. - All right, good.
-当然可以  -很好
We run missions into the city every day.
我们每天在城里都有行动
I'll put you with our field tech, tell him how to operate it.
我把战地技术人员找来  你教他怎么操作
I wouldn't put a tech in between this camera and myself.
我不想让我之外的第二个人来操作这部摄像机
So, you wanna operate it?
那你想亲自操作
If you want that kill shot...
要想拍到关键画面...
you'll need a fast reaction time out there.
需要快速的临场反应
Next mission, you ride with delta.
下次行动  你跟三角洲部队一起
They're gonna get you close to this thing.
他们会带你接近那东西
You get me the kill shot...
等你给我搞到关键画面
you can go home to Virginia without unpacking.
你就可以直接拎包回弗吉尼亚
Got a bad rotor, you gotta swap that out.
有个转子坏了  你得把它换掉
Weld it onto the front panel.
把它焊在前面板上
Well, well, well. Toll, check that out.
瞧瞧这个
- What's this guy up to, man? - I don't know.
-这家伙在做什么  -我不知道
Believe this guy?
你相信这家伙吗
- If it works. - For real.
-如果有作用的话  -说真的
Heard you're installing a camera on our truck.
听说你要在我们的车上装个摄像机
Which was fine until you ripped out that 50 Cal.
要是你不把50口径机枪拆下来我本来没意见
You're taking down a gun to put up a camera?
你拆了把枪换了部摄像机上去
It's the only place large enough to mount it.
只有那里有空间放置摄像机
You guys get that, right? I know it sounds like a terrible idea.
你们能明白吧  我知道这听起来像个坏主意
We prefer to dance with who brung us...
我们更喜欢跟带我们的人合作
Dr. Clyne. You get that, right?
克莱恩博士  懂了吗
"Dance with who brung you"? No, actually, I don't.
"跟带你们的人合作"  我并不懂
This truck has saved our lives, many times.
这辆车救过我们的命很多次
I understand.
我明白
You guys know Dr. Clyne's team built that truck?
你们知道这辆车是克莱恩博士的团队制造的吗
Clyne works over at DARPA.
克莱恩博士在DARPA工作
I've worked closely with his group.
我跟他的团队紧密合作过
Been to their facilities in Virginia.
去过他们在弗吉尼亚的设施
Good to see you, Dr. Clyne.
很高兴见到你  克莱恩博士
Good to see you, Captain Cabrera.
我也是  卡布瑞拉上尉
They retrofitted these trucks with tougher, lighter weight armor.
他们给这些车改装了更坚固轻便的装甲
They designed the mechanical loaders that do the heavy lifting,
他们设计了装载机来搬运重物
so you boys don't strain yourselves too hard.
给你们省了力气
Matter of fact, Dr. Clyne himself
事实上  克莱恩博士本人
developed the thin weight Kevlar body stocking that literally...
还设计了轻薄的凯夫拉连体紧身衣
protects your balls.
来保护你们的蛋蛋
So, I would think there'd be
我希望你们
nothing but goodwill in this group for Dr. Clyne.
都能对克莱恩博士心存感激
- Major Sessions. - Captain, have your men fall back.
-塞申斯少校  -上尉  让你的人退下
- Get back to it. - Get it done.
-都散开  -把它放下
Major, this is Dr. Clyne.
少校  这位是克莱恩博士
He's worked with us eight or ten times over the last five years.
在过去五年他和我们合作过多次
You go out with the assault team on hunting ghost?
你要和突击队一起去击杀鬼影吗
No, sir.
不  长官
He's a good man, major.
他是个好人  少校
That's great. I'm just not a fan of taking tourists on combat missions.
很好  但我不喜欢带游客执行作战任务
Sir, I'm not a tourist.
长官  我不是游客
If you're not carrying an M4, you're a tourist.
如果没携带突击步枪  那你就是个游客
I can carry one, if you'd like.
如果你坚持  我可以配枪
Major, we gotta get Dr. Clyne out in the field
少校  我们得把克莱恩博士带去战场
so he can track the target force and get us a kill shot.
这样他才能追踪目标  帮助我们击毙它
How long before this equipment's operational?
这个仪器需要多久才能运转
A few hours.
几个小时吧
- Is it gonna work? - If we get close enough.
-会有用吗  -如果我们离得够近
Let me tell you something. Sergeant Davis...he got close enough.
戴维斯中士...就离得够近了
That's the best delta that we had.
他是我们最顶尖的三角洲队员
Make sure your equipment is top-notch this time.
最好保证你的仪器也是最顶尖的
- They were like brothers. - I get it.
-他们情同手足  -我理解
Okay.
好吧
Evening, doc.
晚上好  博士
Hear you two hit it off bigtime.
听说你俩一见如故
- She can come off a bit intense. - Yeah. So can you.
-她可以放松一点  -你也是
I'm just here to find this thing.
我来这儿只是帮你们找到这东西
You're willing to go on a combat mission to find it.
为了找到它  你都愿意参与作战任务
She is, too.
她也是
She's under a lot of pressure from D.C.
华盛顿给她施加了太大的压力
They want an answer and it's her job to give them one.
他们想要答案  而她负责找出答案
Saw your names on a mission roster.
在任务名单上看到了你们的名字
I knew this was a top priority...
我知道这是最紧要的事
but for them to embed you both...
但他们把你们俩都派来...
Well, you don't have to worry about me.
不用担心我
I'm not worried about you, doc. I'm worried about it.
我不担心你  博士  我担心这东西
She's hoping it's cloaking technology.
她认为这是一种隐形技术
What do you think it is?
你觉得呢
Something no one's thought of yet.
我们都还没想到的某种东西
Gentlemen, yesterday at 1800 hours,
各位  昨天18点
Utah team left here on a recon mission to Durlesti,
U组去杜勒斯地执行侦察任务时
when they were engaged by insurgents.
与叛军交火了
We managed to hear most of their chatter during the firefight,
我们设法弄清交火时他们说了什么
but comes were unreliable.
但结果并不理想
Target is a five-story apartment building here.
目标是这里的一栋五层建筑
We think what's left of utah team is being held on the fourth floor,
我们认为活着的U组队员被关押在四楼
in the northwest corner apartment.
位于西北角的房间里
We're gonna be knee-deep in an insurgent-held area in the city.
我们将深入叛军占领区域
So, we should expect a fight.
所以  做好交战准备
One last thing.
最后一件事
Before our guys were grabbed,
我们的人被抓住之前
they radioed in that they saw
通过无线电汇报了看到的东西
what we're now calling hyperspectral anomalies.
我们称之为  超光谱异形物
Your mission is a quick extraction.
此次任务要速战速决
You get our guys and you get out.
找到U组队员  带他们出来
However, if engaged, neutralize the anomalies in the area.
如果交火  将异形物就地消灭
Neutralize them?
消灭他们
- How? - Yeah, what are we dealing with here?
-怎么消灭  -我们要对付的是什么
We believe these are enemy soldiers in advanced electronic camouflage.
我们认为是穿着先进电子伪装服的敌方士兵
So, be surgical when you fire. If they are...
所以  交火时务必小心  如果他们...
If we don't really know what they are, maybe we should...
如果不清楚他们是什么  也许我们该...
Excuse me? Would you like to add something?
不好意思  你想补充什么吗
If they are wearing cloaking technology,
如果他们穿戴了隐形技术
you need to bring it back as intact as possible.
你们要尽可能将其完好无损地带回来
Dr. Clyne and Agent Madison will be on mission with you.
克莱恩博士和麦迪逊特工会和你们一起去
Dr. Clyne will be monitoring your helmet-cam feeds
克莱恩博士会在车队中第二辆反伏击车上
from the second MRAP vehicle in the convoy.
监测你们头盔摄像机的反馈影像
Major Sessions will lead dagger team 1 to do the extraction.
塞申斯少校会带领D组1队进行营救
Stay on come. Get your gear.
拿好装备  随时待命
Partner, let's go.
走吧  伙计
AJ, front and center.
AJ  检查前部和中部
Weapons check, Billy.
检查武器  比利
You got it.
没问题
Our ride not smooth enough for you?
这路对你来说不够平坦吗
They really need to repave these roads, man.
他们真应该重新铺一下这条路  兄弟
All right, guys, we're coming into the abandoned zone.
好了  伙计们  我们正在进入废弃区
Expect a heavy insurgent presence.
做好面对大批叛军的准备吧
Okay.
慢点
I've got an insurgent body here.
我发现了一具叛军的尸体
I got Agopia from Utah team. Confirmed KIA.
我发现了U组的高皮  确认阵亡
None of these guys appear to have taken any rounds.
他们都没有交火的迹象
No entry or exit wounds.
没有明显外伤
Alessio here. Moving to the fifth floor.
阿莱西奥汇报  向五楼移动中
- We got movement in there. - Toll, check your 2 o'clock.
-那边有动静  -托尔  两点钟方向
Where? We don't see anything.
哪里  我们什么也没看见
- That's it. Right there. - You're right on top of it.
-没错  就在那儿  -你就在它上方
It's a motion signature. There's something under that tub.
有活动迹象  浴缸下有东西
Lewis, the tub. I want you to flip over the tub.
路易斯  浴缸  把浴缸翻过来
- Toll, I want you on what's underneath. - I'm on it.
-托尔  你负责查看下面是什么  -好的
One, two, three.
一  二  三
We have Comstock alive and conscious.
是科姆斯托克  他还活着并且有意识
Repeat. We have Sergeant Comstock from Utah team.
重复  发现U组的科姆斯托克中士
Hey, buddy.
伙计
- Where's the rest of your team? - They're upstairs.
-你们组的其他人呢  -他们在楼上
But they're all gone. Got under their skin.
但他们都死了  钻到皮肤下面了
- What got under their skin... ? - I saw it.
-什么钻到皮肤下面了  -我看到它了
- But...? - Blanket.
-但是...  -毛毯
Like a frozen blanket.
像一条冰冻的毛毯
- Okay, where is the rest of Utah? - Oh, they're dead.
-U组的其他人呢  -他们死了
Yeah, they're all dead.
他们都死了
We're all dead.
我们都死了
- Where are the bodies? - I told you, they're on the top floor.
-尸体在哪  -我说了  在顶楼
Oh, you haven't seen it.
你还没见过它吧
I've seen it. You know I believe in God, John.
我见过了  你知道我信仰上帝  约翰
This is the opposite of god.
它是上帝的对立面
Wait wait wait. Who's this right there? Can you tell him to turn back?
等等  这是谁  能让他转个身吗
McFadden, turn back.
麦克法登  转过身去
Give us a view of that room.
让我们看看那个房间
Nothing's there, guys. I'm standing right here.
什么也没有  我就站在这儿呢
Mac, we're both staring right at it.
麦克  我们正看着它呢
It's in the middle of your view port.
就在你视线中央
What? That? It's a smear.
什么  那个吗  只是个污点而已
Probably these piece-of-shit goggles.
大概是这破护目镜的问题
No, no, no. Tell him to put them back on.
不不不  让他戴上护目镜
Mac, put the goggles back on.
麦克  把护目镜戴上
Mac, do it now.
麦克  立刻戴上
- What the...? - Take the shot.
-什么情...  -开火
Did you see that? The bullets right through it.
看到了吗  子弹直接穿过了它
- Did he miss? - He doesn't miss.
-他射偏了吗  -没射偏
Major Sessions, we have a KIA. McFadden.
塞申斯少校  麦克法登阵亡了
A hyperspectral target is on the fifth floor, northwest corner.
超光谱异形物在五楼  西北角
Switch to heavy rounds or 203s.
换重型子弹或203s
Whatever you have to do to bring this thing down.
无论如何把这东西放倒
Tell your man to pull out.
让他们撤退
There!
在那儿
Get everyone out now!
让他们立刻出来
Tell them to pull out now.
让他们立刻撤退
No, no way, we're not leaving empty-handed.
不行  我们不能空手而归
I can guarantee you're leaving empty-handed.
你肯定会空手而归的
Come on!
快撤
Grenade!
手雷
- We need support! - Get out.
-我们需要支援  -撤退
All units evacuate now. Let's go. Get back to the truck.
所有队伍立刻撤退  快走  回到车里
- This room right here. We can still grab him. - Let's go! Move!
-就在这里  我们还能带上他  -快撤
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
快走  快点
Go!
快
Here. Here, Jim. Hold on. Here.
这里  这里  吉姆  等等  这里
Evacuating via south face!
从南面撤离
I got Talbot, Comstock,
我和塔尔博特  科姆斯托克
Riedel and Shaire.
里德尔还有谢立
Five men down!
五人阵亡
We gotta travel together
我们一起走
and we gotta stay tight. Can you do that?
要跟紧了  你能行吗
Oh, Jesus. Go!
天啊  走
Come on. Come on.
快点  快点
Move. Move, move.
让开  让开  让开
You got him? Let's go.
扶着他  赶紧走
Get out of the way.
给我闪开
Where?
在哪
- Right there! - Where is it?
-就在那  -它在哪
In front.
前方
We gotta get in.
得赶紧上车
- Help him in. - Come on!
-把他拉进去  -快点
- Get in here! - In you go.
-快进来  -进去
No.
不
Go, go!
跑  快跑
- Move! - Get in.
-跑啊  -上车
We're in! Go!
我们上车了  走吧
Hold on, where's Cabrera? Where's the captain?
卡布瑞拉在哪  上尉在哪
Talk to me. Did you see him?
说话  你看见他了吗
- Come on, talk to me, man. - I saw him die.
-回答我  -我看着他阵亡的
- What? - I saw him die.
-什么  -我看着他阵亡的
- I'm going home. - Yeah.
-我想回家  -没问题
- I'm going home. - Hey, hey, hey. It's okay.
-我想回家  -没事的
Look at me. Look at me.
看着我
- Did you see it? - Yeah.
-你看见它了吗  -是的
You saw it. How close did you get?
你看见它了  你离它有多近
I was in a room with it for hours.
我和它共处一室长达几小时
That tub saved my life.
浴缸救了我的命
I could feel it.
我能感觉到它的存在
Land mines! Hold on!
有地雷  坐稳了
Hey, buddy, look at me. No, no, no.
伙计  看着我  别死啊
Shit.
该死
Open the door.
把门打开
- Come on. Now, move. - Come on.
-快走  -来
Both drivers are dead.
两名司机都阵亡了
Archer Lima 2. Hit a land mine.
呼叫基地  我们遭遇地雷
Both vehicles destroyed.
两辆装甲车都已被炸毁
We are...
我们在
three clicks southeast of target building.
目标建筑的东南方三公里处
We are losing your transmission.
我们听不到你们的无线电
Your transponders are down.
你们的无线电坏了
No shit. Our vehicles were just blown to hell.
废话  我们的装甲车都被炸飞了
We need to find cover.
我们得找掩体
I can't hear what you're saying.
我听不清你说的话
Clyne, leave the camera.
克莱恩  别管摄像机了
Come on, clyne.
快走  克莱恩
Go, go, go.
快快快
Move, move.
快走
Cover.
掩护
- Let's go. - Get up, get up.
-快走  -快起来
Come on.
走
Go, go, go.
走走走
Where you been?
你去哪了
Clear.
安全
Who's injured?
谁受伤了
- Diaz? - I think my ankle's broke.
-迪亚兹  -我脚踝好像受伤了
We need an airlift. I can't get a signal to base.
我们需要空运  但我联系不上基地
Keep trying.
继续尝试
Com.
通讯设备给我
Archer Lima 2. Archer Lima 2.
呼叫基地  呼叫基地
This is Dagger team 1, over.
这里是D组1队  收到请回答
I'm good. I'm good.
我没事
Can they get in that way?
它们能从那里进来吗
You all right?
你没事吧
Archer Lima 2, this is Dagger team 1.
呼叫基地  这里是D组1队
Do you copy? Over.
收到请回答
Archer Lima 2, this is Dagger team 1. Do you copy? Over.
呼叫基地  这里是D组1队  收到请回答
How you doing? You're bleeding.
你怎么样  你在流血
Okay.
没事了
You hit your head.
你撞到头了
Did you black out?
你晕过去了吗
Yeah, I guess so.
好像是的
Major.
少校
- She hit her head pretty bad. - Let me see.
-她的头撞得挺严重的  -我看看
Pupils are huge.
瞳孔很大
Sir, I'm sending but they're not receiving.
长官  我一直在发信号但他们收不到
I'm hearing a click back as soon as I sign over, but no answer.
我发完后能听到滴答声  但是没有应答
Keep trying.
继续尝试
She's in shock. Keep an eye on her.
她吓得不轻  照看好她
Archer Lima 2, this is Dagger team 1. Do you copy? Over.
呼叫基地  这里是D组1队  收到请回答
... over there.
...去那边
Where's everyone else? Where's the rest of Utah?
其他人呢  U组其他人在哪
I'm Sergeant Chen. I was with Utah.
我是陈中士  我是U组的
We were the second team in last night. There was eight of us.
我们是昨晚第二个来的小组  来了八个
Do you have confirmed KIAs for Utah?
你们能确认U组谁已经阵亡了吗
Well, I can tell you this much.
我只能告诉你
Sergeant Comstock's not gonna be on your team Christmas card this year.
科姆斯托克中士今年收不到圣诞贺卡了
- You saw insurgents kill Comstock? - Insurgents?
-你看到叛军杀了科姆斯托克  -叛军
Is this guy for real?
他没毛病吧
- What rock were you under? - I was the radio operator.
-你在哪躲着呢  -我是通讯兵
We lost com. I was stuck in the truck the whole night.
我们失去联系了  我整晚都被困在卡车里
- I never saw the active camouflage. - Active camouflage?
-我没见到动态伪装兵  -动态伪装兵
Even if there was a such thing, and there's not...
根本就没有这样的士兵  就算有
How does a human wearing active camouflage walk through walls?
人类怎么可能穿着动态伪装服穿过墙壁呢
Or through three mags of armor-piercing ammo?
或被三个弹夹的穿甲弹打穿都没死
I saw Pat pump 150 rounds at one of them.
我看到帕特对其中一个打了至少150发
This thing's killed at least 19 of our men.
这东西至少杀了19个我们的人
And we have no idea what it is.
而我们还不知道它是什么东西
Clyne.
克莱恩
You saw it.
你见过它
What was it?
它是什么东西
Human.
是人类
Had a human form.
有着人类的外形
It looked at me, it was conscious.
它看着我  有自己的意识
Like a person.
就像个活人
Is there anything that explains what you saw?
有什么能解释你看到的东西吗
No.
没有
Let's pull together all the functional goggles that we have.
我们把能用的护目镜收集起来
My goggles were wasted in the crash, sir.
我的护目镜在撞击中坏了
Yeah. Mine, too. They're trashed.
我的也是  撞坏了
Forget the goggles. We can't recharge them anyway.
别管护目镜了  反正我们也没办法充电
So, what do we do?
那我们怎么办
How are we supposed to see them?
我们怎么发现它们
Maybe that camera can still help us.
也许那台摄像机还能帮上忙
If we get to an elevated position,
如果能占领制高点
we'd have a better vantage point.
情况可能对我们更有利
Help me with this?
来搭把手
Let's go. Let's move out. Move.
我们走  行动起来
They're everywhere.
到处都是
Something's stopping them.
有什么东西阻挡住了它们
Some sort of black sand.
某种黑色沙土
I fell in that sand.
我在那沙里摔了一跤
- I had to... pick it out of my hand. - Let me see it.
-我把它从手里抠出来了  -让我看看
- Little, sharp pieces of metal. - They're iron filings.
-一小片尖锐金属  -是铁屑
- It's pure iron. - Yeah.
-纯铁  -是啊
And there's a trail of it... All the way around the building.
一整条铁屑  围绕房子一圈
It's a barrier. Someone put it there.
这是一道屏障  有人把它放在那的
I don't think we're alone.
看来这里还有人
Let's stack up and sweep upstairs.
整理好装备  我们清理楼上
Point and shoot?
瞄准就开枪
Breach! Breach!
突进  突进
- I've got kids. - Clear.
-发现儿童  -安全
- Clear. - All clear.
-安全  -解除警报
Tell them to take the long wall.
派人守住长墙那里
Ask them where they got this, and who else is here.
问他们枪从哪来的  这里还有谁
Ask them if there's anyone
问问他们工厂里
else in the factory, and do they have guns.
是否还有其他人  以及他们是否有枪
She says they're here alone.
她说只有她们俩在这里
Only that one gun. No soldiers are here.
就那一把枪  没有士兵
- No one at all. - Major sessions.
-一个人都没有  -塞申斯少校
What's the problem?
出什么问题了
This factory has its own transmission tower.
这工厂有自己的信号塔
It puts out a huge signal.
能发出很强的信号
So, what's the problem?
有什么问题吗
Everyone within 20 miles
32公里内的所有人
will hear our conversation with base.
都能听见我们和基地的通话
Any insurgent radio will pick up our transmission.
任何叛军的电台都能截获我们的信号
Insurgents are the least of your worries.
现在最不用担心的就是叛军
Connect me to General Orland as soon as possible.
尽快和奥伦德将军取得联系
Archer Lima 2, Archer Lima 2, this is Dagger team.
呼叫基地  这里是D组
Do you copy?
能收到吗
You guys are our new recruits.
你们是我们的新兵
And believe me... we could use the help.
相信我  你们能帮上大忙
Come on, tough guy. Show me what you got.
来吧  小铁汉  看看你有什么本事
Hey, I need to ask you something.
我得问你些事儿
Was it your idea... to put the barrier... outside?
外面的屏障  是你的主意吗
Their father. Their father knew.
是他们父亲  他们父亲知道
Their father rolled open barrels of the iron shavings
他们父亲沿着建筑外围
around the building.
撒了几桶铁屑
He saved their lives.
他救了他们的命
What happened to your father?
你父亲呢
You're a little scrapper, aren't you?
你是个小拳击手是吧
Hey, buddy, you all right? Come on, get up.
伙计  你没事吧  继续  站起来
What are you doing?
你在做什么
Are you a ghost?
你是鬼魂吗
Aratare.
幽魂
He says, "Don't say that word."
他说别说那个词
Ask him what they are.
问他那些东西是什么
Lost souls.
失落的灵魂
Souls of the dead.
死者的灵魂
They're trapped between life and death,
被困在生与死之间
and they can't find peace.
无法安息
How's that happen?
为什么会这样
He says, "War."
他说是因为战争
Come on.
过来
If their father was the one who put down the iron shavings,
如果是他们的父亲撒下了那些铁屑
he knows more about these things than any of us do.
那他比我们任何人都更了解那些东西
Ask her where her father is.
问问她父亲在哪儿
Her brother, Bogdan, doesn't know.
她弟弟波格丹还不知道
He thinks he went to get help.
他以为父亲只是出去求助了
He died outside, when he was making the barrier.
他是在外面弄屏障的时候死的
She had to bring him in here.
她只能把他带回这里
I'm so sorry.
我很遗憾
- Okay? - Yeah.
-我可以吗  -嗯
Ceramic tile.
陶瓷片
Ask her how her father knew
问问她父亲是怎么知道
about the iron filings stopping the Aratare.
铁屑能阻挡幽魂的
What else did he know about them?
他还知道些什么
She doesn't know.
她什么都不知道
"Masarov."
马萨罗维
- What is Masarov? - It's a place.
-马萨罗维是什么  -是一个地名
It's a district up the river.
上游的一个区域
It's where it all began.
是这一切的源头
It's where the Aratare killings started.
幽魂杀人就是从那里开始的
Aratare.
幽魂
I'm saying we land the helos right here.
要我说就把直升机停这儿
Extract us from this roof and get us the hell out of here.
我们从这个屋顶撤离  赶紧离开这里
There are phone lines and power lines everywhere.
这里到处都是电话线和电力线
The helos would have to fly low and slow.
直升机得飞得又低又慢
Easy pickings for a teenager with a shoulder rocket.
一个小孩都能扛着火箭筒把它打下来
Major, can you get me up to speed?
少校  现在是什么情况
You spoke with base?
和基地联系过了吗
Yeah. The General's sending in helos to come get us,
联系过了  将军会派直升机来接我们
and tanks to secure the landing zone in an open plaza
以及坦克来确保降落广场周边安全
about half a mile from here, at dawn.
距这里约八百米  黎明到达
That's a long way on foot.
步行的话会很远
You think we can make it a half mile? With kids?
你觉得我们能带着小孩撑过八百米吗
We don't have an option. Okay?
我们别无选择
All the roads are either blocked or mined.
所有的路要么被封死要么埋了地雷
And since we used signal tower to talk to base,
而且我们用信号塔和基地联系了
everyone knows where we are.
所有人都知道我们的位置
We gotta move out.
我们得尽快出去
So you wanna go running around out there
那些东西还在街上乱晃
with those things roaming the streets?
你想在这种情况下出去吗
Even though we have no way to see or fight?
我们还没有任何看到和对付它们的办法
Better than waiting for them to find a way in here.
总比等着它们闯进来要好
How is it better?
哪里好了
The only reason we're still alive is that barricade out there.
我们没死的唯一原因就是外面的那道屏障
Look, eventually they're gonna get through.
它们迟早会进来的
It's just a matter of time.
只是时间问题
- Wait, wait, wait. - We have to take our chances.
-先消停一下  -我们得冒险一试
- This is the best plan that we have. - Major.
-这是目前最好的计划  -少校
What if I told you I can improve our chances of making that plaza?
如果我说我能增加成功到达广场的几率呢
- I'm listening. - Take a look around you.
-你说  -看看周围
Everything in this building... is filled with these.
这里到处都是这东西
Iron dust.
铁屑
And the iron stops the hyperspectrals.
铁能阻止那些超光谱异形
Exactly. Weaponize it.
没错  把它做成武器
- Dirty bombs. - Best idea I've heard all night.
-脏弹  -这是今晚最好的主意
Let's collect the grenades.
收集手榴弹
Clyne.
克莱恩
I need you to be our eyes out there.
在外面我需要你做我们的眼睛
Can you haul that camera on foot?
你能带着摄像机走路吗
I've got a better idea.
我有更好的主意
This camera already projects the right wavelength of UV light.
这个摄像机本身就能投射相符波长的紫外线
If I can turn it inside out,
如果我能将它内部翻转过来
by reversing the polarity of some of the components,
通过改变一些结构的极性
I might be able to turn it from a camera into a searchlight.
我也许能把摄像机改造成探照灯
We'll be able to see them with our own eyes.
我们凭肉眼就能看见它们
That'd be a game-changer.
这能大大改善我们的境况
Think I can talk to the convoy?
我能和基地的车队通话吗
I might be albe to tell them
我或许能告诉它们
how to do the same with their equipment.
如何对装备做同样的调整
When they come get us, they're gonna need eyes, too.
他们过来时也需要能看见它们的设备
I'll connect you to the main engineer back at base.
我会帮你联系基地的主工程师
Copy that.
收到
They're ready to equip their vehicles with whatever you need.
他们会在车上装备任何你需要的东西
Can you repeat the whole request back to me, please?
能将需求列表复述一遍给我吗
Okay, yes. That's correct.
对  没错
But what you gonna need is a device
但你需要的是一个
that emits a very short wavelength of light.
能发射短波长光的装置
I can tell you exactly how to rewire that.
我会详细告诉你怎么改线
Do you have anything you can mount on a tank?
有什么可以装在坦克上的东西吗
We got movement across the alleyway.
小巷那头有动静
Guys, we got movement. Can we get eyes on it?
伙计们  有动静  能看看是什么吗
Hey, guys, stand clear for a second.
麻烦让一下
What's the word on the convoy?
车队那边怎么说
Last contact was 50 minutes ago.
上次通讯在50分钟以前
They're on their way to the extraction point.
他们在前往撤离点的路上
Here they come! Get your gear.
它们来了  拿好你们的装备
We're leaving this building in 15 seconds.
我们15秒后离开这里
Okay, come on. Let's go.
快  我们走
That was the fastest way to the extraction point.
那是去撤离点最快的路线
Hey. She says she can show us another way.
她说可以带我们走另一条路
Talbot, you're with Clyne.
塔尔博特  你和克莱恩一起
Diaz, you're on point.
迪亚兹  你领头
Let's go.
我们走
Yup. Moving.
没问题  继续走
Okay, let's go.
好  我们走
Come on.
跟上
Come here.
这边
Everybody's accounted for.
所有人都在
- It looks clear. - Let's move. Come here.
-看起来没问题  -我们走  这边
Okay. She says, "Go right here."
好  她说这里右拐
Hey. Heads up, 6 o'clock.
注意  六点钟方向
- Move! - Move!
-快走  -快走
Move!
快走
They're coming.
它们来了
Come on.
跟上
Watch out!
当心
Oh, shit.
见鬼
Come on, Lewis! Let's go!
快  路易斯  我们走
I think it's working!
我觉得起作用了
- In here! - This way.
-进来  -这边
Move, move.
快走  快走
Go!
走
- Move it! - Come on.
-快跟上  -跟上
- Pick up! - Get up.
-扶他起来  -起来
- I'm good. - Go! Go!
-我没事  -走  快走
Steady your gun!
把枪拿稳
- Get down! - Take cover, man.
-趴下  -找掩护
Come on, Doctor. Come on.
快  博士  快点
Incoming!
他们来了
I got a man down! Man down!
一人阵亡  一人阵亡
Run!
快跑
- Moving it up! - More on that side!
-快跑  -那边有更多
Hurry.
快点
She says, "Straight ahead, under the archway."
她说"就在前面  拱门下方"
Watch yourself.
小心点
- Hold it. - She says this is the place.
-慢着  -她说就是这里
Go, go.
走  走
Looks clear.
应该安全
- Where are they? - Get on the bus. Go.
-他们在哪里  -快上公交车
Where's the rescue?
救援在哪里
Where's the light?
灯光呢
Come on. Come on, come on. Work. Work. Work.
拜托  亮起来
Come on. It's okay.
振作点  没事的
You sure this is the place?
你确定就是这里吗
- Yeah. - Ask them if they're sure.
-是的  -问他们是否确定
She said, "I'm pretty sure."
她说"我非常确定"
Major.
少校
This thing is dead. We can't see them.
这玩意坏了  我们没法看到他们
We're blind.
看不到了
- That's us. - This is the landing zone.
-是我们的人  -这里就是着陆区
- Commander, are you seeing this? - Those are the targets.
-指挥官  你看到了吗  -那些就是目标
- Go! Go! Go! - Go!
-走  走  走  -快
- Go, go, go. - Let's go.
-走  走  走  -快走
Move. Go on.
快走
On the ground.
向下俯身
Fire.
开火
Get down!
伏低
- Move on my command. - Move it out!
-听我的命令行动  -前进
Overhead!
上方
Let's get to the tanks! Move it to the tanks!
快到坦克那里  移动到坦克
- Move it! - Move!
-快走  -走
Move!
走
- Open fire! - Let it go!
-开火  -射击
- Get back! - No.
-撤回去  -不
Get back!
撤回去
Left flank!
在左边
Your six!
正后方
- Where are they? - I don't know!
-他们在哪里  -我不知道
- Where's Bogdan? - Where'd he go?
-波格丹在哪里  -他去哪里了
- Who's got him? - Do you see them?
-谁和他一起  -你看到他们了吗
We'll find you!
我们会找到你的
- Bogdan! - Bogdan!
-波格丹  -波格丹
Get him!
带他回来
Bogdan! Bogdan!
波格丹  波格丹
- Bogdan! - Get back here!
-波格丹  -回来
Get back here!
回来
- Come on! - Come on.
-快点  -走吧
- Take her. - Get up.
-扶着她  -起来
Help her! Save her!
帮帮她  救救她
I got her.
我扶住她了
Let's go.
我们走
Come on!
快走
- Get up. Come on. - Dr. Clyne, come on!
-站起来  快  -克莱恩博士  快走
- Get in! - Okay.
-上去  -好了
Major. General Orland.
少校  是奥伦德将军
General, go for sessions.
将军  请说
Base has been lost!
基地已沦陷
We're sending you to our refugee bunker!
我们正带你们去避难所
Yes, sir.
好的  长官
Hey, where are we going? Base is that way.
我们要去哪里  基地在那边
- We're not going to base. - Why not?
-我们不去基地了  -为什么不去
It's been compromised.
基地已被攻陷
Hey, they're spreading through the streets.
他们正扩散到街上
They're everywhere.
到处都是
They just gonna leave us here?
他们就把我们留在这里吗
There's more people to airlift.
有更多的人要运载
- What is this place? - Entrance is over here.
-这里是什么地方  -入口就在那边
Open the door! Open the door!
打开门  打开门
Get back!
退后
Put your weapons down.
放下你们的武器
Put your weapons down! Do it now!
放下你们的武器  立刻放下
He's saying, "Safe inside."
他说"里面安全"
Okay. It's okay.
没事了  没事了
Stay close.
跟紧
Hey, hey, hey. Look at me. Look at me.
看着我  看着我
She's not okay. Come here.
她不怎么好  过来
I'm gonna need some room. It's okay. It's okay.
需要找个地方  没事的  没事的
What the hell happened to base?
基地究竟出什么事了
Base got overrun.
基地被攻陷了
The general is meeting us here.
将军会在这里跟我们见面
So, what is this place?
这是什么地方
We're in a civilian refugee shelter.
我们在民用的避难所
This bunker has 20 feet of concrete and steel.
这避难所有六米厚的钢筋混凝土
Are we safe here? I have no idea. But there's food and water.
我不知道在这里是否安全  但有食物和水
Talbot, gather what you can.
塔尔博特  尽可能收集物资
Toll, chen, head back to the entrance.
托尔  陈  回到入口处
There's a com center. See who you can reach.
那里有通讯中心  看能联络到谁
Alessio, you're with me. Let's go.
阿莱西奥  你和我一起  走吧
- There. - Where?
-那边  -哪里
- There. - Right over there.
-那边  -就在那里
- Okay. - On the bed.
-好的  -放到床上
You're okay. Shh. You're gonna be okay.
没事的  你会没事的
- What happened? - It's her shoulder.
-怎么了  -是她的肩膀
- Her shoulder has shrapnel in it.
-她的肩膀里有弹片
- We're gonna cut open her sleeve.
-我们要剪开衣袖
Get the IV line ready.
准备静脉输液管
This is yours.
这是你的
Now, I need your help, Sari, to stop the aratare.
莎莉  我现在需要你帮忙  为了阻止幽魂
I need to know what your father knew.
我必须知道你爸爸所知道的
What did your father do?
你爸爸是做什么的
He worked with ceramics.
他是制陶的
What did he make?
他制作些什么呢
He made containers.
他制造容器
He made containers for Masarov.
他为马萨罗维制造容器
The power plant where the aratare came from.
幽魂就是来自那里的发电厂
Let's get the mask on her.
让她带上氧气面罩
Okay, we have to take her now.
现在她得交给我们了
- This is the U.S. armed forces! - Open it.
-我们是美国军队  -开门
Lower your weapons.
放下武器
- How many are you? - Not many.
-你们有多少人  -不怎么多
Let's give them a hand.
帮一下他们
Let's go.
走吧
Bring as much as you can.
尽可能多带点
The base was overrun.
基地被攻陷了
It was like a wave.
那东西就像一道波浪
Invisible.
隐形的波浪
Men just started falling.
大家就开始倒下
Our conventional weapons were useless.
我们的常规武器毫无作用
I requested an order to evacuate the base...
我请求下令撤离基地...
But our long-range come are completely scrambled.
但远距离通讯系统完全被扰乱
So, I took all the gear I could.
所以我把能带的装备都带上
I started sending units north out of the area of operation.
开始让各小队向北撤离行动区
Kept five aircraft with the least amount of fuel,
让五架飞机保持最小耗燃量
stayed behind with one platoon.
跟着一个排殿后
Out of the 240 of us, we have 19 remaining.
我们240人只剩下19个了
Did you get a message to higher command?
有成功向上级通报吗
No.
没有
Is there a rescue mission planned?
有安排救援计划吗
No. We intercepted radio chatter
没有  我们截取了
from Moldovan friendlies to find this place.
摩尔多瓦友方无线电信号才找到这里
We sent that bird to pick you up and bring you here.
我们派出直升机接你们过来
If you'd even tried to return to base, you'd be dead.
你们要是试着回基地  就已经没命了
We're the last U.S. Forces in the country?
我们是这个国家最后的美军吗
I hope so.
但愿如此
So, what's the plan, sir?
有什么计划吗  长官
Came here to regroup, Major.
来这里重新部署  少校
There's no plan.
没什么计划
- I recommend we fortify the entrance. - Fortify with what?
-我建议加固入口  -用什么加固
- We wait till a rescue mission... - Fortify with what?
-我们等待救援...  -用什么加固
They'll come through whatever you use.
无论你用什么东西  他们都能穿过
We need to take our chances get on one of our helos...
我们得用直升机碰一碰运气...
Twenty minutes of flight time!
只能飞二十分钟
There's twenty minutes of flight time in those birds.
直升机只剩二十分钟的飞行时间了
Not more!
飞不了更久了
Doesn't matter, there's not enough room for all of us...
没关系  反正也装不下所有人
We need to form teams and take the aircraft.
我们得组队乘飞机
But where you gonna go, Major?
但你要去哪里  少校
You can't run from them.
你们躲不掉它们
You can't stop them. Your weapons are useless.
你们无法阻止它们  你们的武器毫无作用
We have no idea what they are!
我们不知道它们到底是什么
If they come through that door, we're sitting ducks.
要是它们穿门而入  我们只能坐以待毙
We can't stop them! We can't stop them!
我们阻止不了它们  我们阻止不了它们
Take what we can and go.
把我们能带走的都带走
I know what they are.
我知道它们是什么了
We think we're seeing things.
我们觉得我们见鬼了
We think it can't be real, but it kills.
我们觉得它不是真的  但它有杀伤力
So, it is real.
所以它是真的
It's something.
是一种物质
It's not light, it's not shadow,
非光非影
or some trick of the mind. Pass through walls, check.
不是幻觉  可以穿墙  没错
Outside the visible spectrum, check.
属于非可见光谱  没错
Kills to the touch, check.
一触即死  没错
Comstock. He was under a ceramic bathtub, is that right?
科姆斯托克当时躲在瓷浴缸底下  对吧
Tank armor. It couldn't pass through tank armor.
坦克装甲  它不能穿过坦克装甲
M1 Abrams tank armor, that's ceramic plating everywhere.
M1艾布兰主战坦克装甲周身镀瓷
It cannot pass through ceramic.
它不能穿过瓷制品
You know what that means?
你们知道这意味着什么吗
It means this stuff isn't natural.
意味着这东西不是天然的
Someone made it.
有人创造了它
It's man-made.
它是人造的
Man-made how?
怎么人造的
Okay. You have solid, liquid, gas.
世上有固体  液体  气体
Lava can turn into rock.
熔岩可以凝固成岩石
Ice can turn into water.
冰可以融化成水
Metals can melt. These are natural states.
金属能熔化  这些都是自然状态
But there are unnatural states.
但也有非自然状态
Artificial states, man-made states.
人造状态  人创造的状态
Condensate.
凝聚态
Bose-Einstein condensate.
玻色-爱因斯坦凝聚态
A state of matter that was
一种由奈斯·玻色
predicted by Nath Bose and Albert Einstein.
和阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦预测的一种物质状态
It has some very unusual properties.
它有一些非常反常的特性
It can be slowed down by iron filings.
会被铁屑减速
It cannot pass through ceramic, but it can pass through walls.
它不能穿过瓷制品  但却可以穿墙
It's so cold it will kill you instantly on contact.
温度太低以致于一触即死
It can do everything we've been seeing here.
它可以解释我们所见的一切
You want to create Bose-Einstein condensate.
要想产生波色-爱因斯坦凝聚态
You need power, and you need a lot of it.
你们需要能量  大量的能量
Masarov. The power plant.
马萨罗维  那个核电站
Yes, Masarov. Where they were made.
对  马萨罗维  它们的制造地
You said this country was pouring billions into weapons research.
你说这个国家在武器研究上投资数十亿
This is a weapon.
这就是武器
And it was set loose, or it broke loose.
这要么是有意释放  要么是意外爆发
All right, but these things climb.
好吧  但这些东西会爬
They're like human beings. It looks like a person.
它们就像人类  看起来像人一样
So can marble and clay in the right hands.
大理石和泥土也能塑成人型
And I wanna know why.
我想知道为什么
Why they look like people.
它们为什么看起来像人
I can't tell you how they did this.
我不知道它们是怎么做的
What I can tell you... is that someone made them.
我只能告诉你它们是人造的
If someone made them,
如果是人造的
they don't escape the laws of the world.
它们就逃不开世界的规律
Nothing does.
没有东西能逃开
It shines light on new laws, and that's what we have to learn.
它适用于我们需要了解的新规律
Cause they have order and structure.
因为它们有序有结构
They can be broken down.
它们就可以被瓦解
Anything can be broken down. It's just energy.
任何东西都可以被瓦解  全看所需的能量
And cause I know what they are,
因为我已经知道了它们是什么
I know the properties, I can build the right weapons.
知道了特性  我就可以造出对应的武器
What kind of weapons look like?
什么样的武器
Plasmic-discharge weapons. They can tear apart the condensate.
等离子放电枪  它们可以瓦解凝聚态
Where do you expect that we can find weapons like that?
你让我们上哪里找那种武器
We're not gonna find them, we're gonna build them.
我们不找  我们自己造
Build them with what?
用什么造
Anything we can find in this bunker.
能在掩体里找到的所有东西
Anything with electronics, optics, ballistic casings.
所有电子学  光学和弹道学的部件
All the gear you brought from base.
所有从基地带来的零件
We can take it all apart, and I can build an arsenal.
我们可以全部拆开  我来造一个军火库
And then we can go to Masarov
接着我们可以去马萨罗维
and we can stop this before it goes any further.
在事态进一步恶化前阻止它
Because if we don't,
因为如果我们不去
the condensate which feed on all the energy in its path
一路汲取所有能量的凝聚态
will grow exponentially.
会呈指数型增长
There's no limit to how far they can spread,
传播的范围将难以估量
unless we stop them.
除非我们阻止它们
Let's get this gear inside, guys. Come on.
伙计们  把零件拖进去  加把劲
Let's move!
行动
Same number each side.
每边的数字一样
All right, let's go, boys!
好了  动起来  兄弟们
Any med patches in there?
有MED部件吗
We got three of them over here.
我在这找到三个
It's a ground-to-air tracking scope.
这是地对空追踪瞄准镜
We can use this. They have good optics.
我们可以用这个  它们光学性能很好
- Good. This is good. - Two more over there.
-好的  这很好  -这边还有两个
See that 305?
看到那个305了吗
Half of these are labeled "Defective."
半数被贴上了"残次品"标签
We're gonna need a voltage counter.
我们需要一个反向电压
I want you to start testing these.
你们现在就开始测试这些东西
All right, open it up.
好了  打开
Get that one open. Pop it.
打开  掀开
Is that what I think it is?
和我想的一样吗
We got the Lotus from base.
我们从基地拿来的路特斯
That's badass.
太厉害了
- Looks like a mechanical rottweiler. - Look at that.
-像一只机械罗特韦尔犬  -看啊
Clyne's making a few changes.
克莱恩做了些调整
They're taking down a chain hoist and putting up a searchlight.
他们在卸下链式起重机  装上探照灯
Déjà vu.
似曾相识嘛
- What does it fire? - It's a focused energy pulse.
-它发射什么  -一种聚焦能量脉冲
If my math is right...
如果我没算错的话
it should break down condensate.
它应该可以瓦解凝聚态
Masarov.
马萨罗维
The single largest power plant in the region.
本地区唯一的最大的核电站
It's where the killings started.
也是死亡的发源地
If they're man-made, they were made here.
如果它们是人造的  那一定就是在这里
It's less than ten klicks from here.
距离这里不到十公里
Our birds can make that, but... it's probably one way.
飞机可以到达  但可能只有一条路
I've been digging for clues with the civilians here.
我一直在当地居民那里挖掘线索
I found this intel on Masarov.
我找到了关于马萨罗维的情报
It's been retrofitted several times over the last decade
在过去十年间  它被中央政权
by the central regime.
翻新过很多次
It's got "Weapons research" written all over it.
表面写满了"武器研究"的字样
Okay, you and Clyne need to be embedded to infiltrate.
好的  你和克莱恩需要潜进去
It's gonna be up to the both of you to figure out how to stop this.
就指望你们弄清楚怎么停止这一切了
We have to create a diversion.
我们得声东击西
We'll draw them out here so you can infiltrate the structure
我们会在这里吸引它们好让你们潜入内部
and try to find the source.
试着找到源头
Clyne's predicting the charge from these weapons will be extremely hot.
克莱恩说这些武器会释放高温电流
Enough to destroy condensate.
足够摧毁凝聚态
We'll find out soon enough.
我们很快就可以验证一下了
All right, boys.
好了  兄弟们
This is it.
就这样了
If you have any last words...
如果还有什么遗言
now's the time.
现在说吧
All right, listen up.
好  听好了
You are using untested weapons...
你们用的是未经测试的武器
against an enemy that, to this point, has been unstoppable.
抵抗此刻看来是无法被击退的敌人
Now, you are heading into unknown territory.
现在你们要前往未知的领地
And hear me when I say
听清楚了
you're gonna see things you will not understand.
你们会看到一些无法理解的东西
Our enemy has spread through the city in a matter of days.
我们的敌人已在数日之内遍布全城
There's no telling how far they will spread...
不知道它们会传播多远
unless we fight back.
除非我们反击
Most men never even come close... to changing the future.
很多人都不曾有机会改变未来
This is the place.
此地
And now is the time.
此刻
Make no mistake, you're the last line of defense.
毫无疑问  你们是最后一道防线
Let's go do what we came here to do.
让我们完成最初的使命
Let's go, let's go!
出发  出发
One minute.
一分钟
Thirty seconds.
三十秒
Spearhead 1, proceed with descent.
先锋一号  准备下降
All right, let's go.
好了  出发
Here we go.
我们走
Let's move!
行动
We have a visual.
发现目标
Hostile target gathering at 12 o'clock on east end of platform.
敌方目标聚集在12点方向平台东端
Move, move!
行动
We are a go.
可以射击
I have a confirmed spectral kill.
确认杀死一只幽魂
We're a go. I say again, all units go.
可以行动  重复  全体行动
- Let's show them what we've got. - Come on.
-让它们看看我们的厉害  -走
- This is it! - Let's do it!
-成败在此一举了  -上吧
Let's go. Drop.
我们上  降落
Copy, Spearhead 1. All units engage.
收到  先锋一队  全体进攻
Spearhead 2 taking north peninsula.
先锋二队控制北半岛
Spearhead 3 beginning descent over south peninsula.
先锋三队开始进攻南半岛
At least a dozen targets coming out.
至少出现了一打目标
- Go! Go! - Let's move!
-进攻  -我们行动
- On me! - All units, you are clear to engage.
-听我命令  -全体人员  允许进攻
- Move in! - Move it!
-进攻  -进攻
Lock and load.
目标锁定  准备射击
- Move out. - Let's move.
-出击  -我们行动
Right behind you!
在你身后
Weapons free! Weapons free!
允许开火  允许开火
Let's go. Move up!
我们走  冲啊
- Move! - Come on!
-冲啊  -快
- I said go, go, go! - Move!
-进攻进攻进攻  -进攻
Spearhead 2, you're go for infield. Proceed to insertion point.
先锋二队  目标内部设施  前往渗入点
Go, go, go!
走走走
Get down!
趴下
Right there.
就在那
- Toll! - Go! Go!
-托尔  -快跑
Go, go, go!
快跑
- Somebody get on top! - Down right there!
-谁去控制高点  -下面出现目标
- We got more incoming! - Keep formation!
-更多目标出现  -保持队形
Let's move it!
前进
Fight! Fight!
进攻  进攻
Move!
进攻
- Let's go, go, go! - Go, John!
-进攻进攻进攻  -冲啊  约翰
- Do we have a sit-rep? - Right now.
-有情况报告吗  -马上
Clyne, what's the situation down there?
克莱恩  下面情况如何
Sessions, we got split up.
塞申斯  我们被分开了
We're still looking for the lab.
还在寻找实验室
We're holding. Don't know how long.
我们还在撑着  不知道能撑多久
- Do you copy? - Can you hear me? Sessions?
-收到了吗  -能听到吗  塞申斯
We gotta keep going.
我们得继续前进
We gotta be close now.
肯定很近了
God.
天哪
Look over here.
看这里
Bose-Einstein condensate.
波色-爱因斯坦凝聚态
Look at these x-rays.
看那些X光线
They were scanning people. On a molecular level.
他们在扫描人类  而且是分子级别的
And printing them out of condensate.
然后用凝聚态打印出来
It's an assembly line.
这是条装配线
Like some kind of...
就像某种...
Industrial process.
工业生产线
You're right.
没错
It's a weapon.
这就是个武器
What happened here?
这里发生了什么
It looks like a catastrophic failure.
看起来像是出现了灾难性故障
Half the cells are broken and empty.
一半单元格破损而且已经空了
Some structural failure must have set them free.
肯定是结构损坏让它们逃了出来
Opened up pandora's box.
打开了潘多拉魔盒
Now what?
现在怎么办
Incoming!
敌人出现
Hey, 12 o'clock!
12点钟方向
- Do it! - It's up! They're coming back together!
-开枪  -它起来了  它们又聚合了
- They're moving! - All eyes on target.
-要来了  -瞄准目标
- One of them is reforming. - Bring it down!
-有一个重新聚合了  -干掉它
"Top research advisers of the central regime."
中央政府高端研究顾问
This man was trying to stop it. They did lose control.
他想要阻止这个局面的  确实是失控了
Can you translate this?
你能翻译这个吗
It's an emergency shutdown procedure.
是紧急关闭程序
Half these words I've never seen.
上面一半的字我都没见过
What about the other half?
另一半写的什么
"Decouple... decouple procedure.
解耦  解耦程序
Disconnect the umbilicals to,
断开脐带链接
uh... interrupt the... neural activity."
以中断神经活动
- Okay. - So, you gotta unlock all these ports.
-好的  -所以你得解锁所有端口
And then you gotta pull
然后拉这个
this bracket here to release all the cables.
操纵杆  断开所有电缆
And then?
然后呢
That should stop them.
应该就能阻止它们了
Take this.
拿着
Come on! Get up!
快点  给我起来
Right there! There's more!
在那里  又增加了
Another one!
又出现一个
Got it right there!
就在那
- Clyne! - I know!
-克莱恩  -我知道
What the hell?
搞什么
I did them all. Nothing's happening.
我都断开了  没有用啊
Clyne! Pull the bracket! In the middle!
克莱恩  拉操纵杆  中间那个
- No! - No!
-不  -不
- Is it over? - I don't know.
-结束了吗  -不知道
Can you walk?
你还能走路吗
- I'm all right. - Come on.
-我没事  -来吧
We have to find a way out.
我们得找条出路
- Do you hear that? - Yeah.
-听到了吗  -听到了
This is it.
是这里了
They weren't just scanning people.
他们不只是扫描人类
They're not just printouts.
它们也不仅仅是打印物
This is what's controlling them.
这是控制他们的东西
These are from real corpses.
这些是真正的尸体
Each one is made from a real person.
每一个都是一条生命
They're alive?
他们都还活着吗
They're not alive.
并非活着
They're not dead.
但也没有死亡
They're just trapped somewhere in between.
他们被困在了生死之间
But they are in pain.
但是十分痛苦
How do you know?
你怎么知道
This is pain.
这就是痛苦
But how do you know they can feel?
那你怎么知道他们能感觉到
I can't prove it.
我无法证明
I can't.
确实
So, maybe there are things science can't answer.
也许科学确实无法回答一切问题
No.
不
Wait, no.
等等  不要
This is why we came here.
这是我们来这里的目的
This is the evidence. This is why you came, remember?
这都是证据  是你来的目的  记得吗
Remember? So many people have died. You said it.
记得吗  已经死了那么多人  你说的
- You said, "I wanna know why." - I know enough.
-你说你要知道原因  -已经够了
You have to think about the bigger picture.
你得为大局考虑
I am.
这就是为大局
Help them off single file.
帮他们依次下机
Got more coming in!
后续还有更多伤员
Put them in unit 5.
送他们去第五小队
- Over here. Over here. - Watch his neck.
-这边这边  -小心他的脖子
Yeah. Yeah, I'm okay.
我没事
Give me your hand.
把手给我
Right there, sir.
这边  先生
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
You okay?
你没事吧
New survey teams.
来了新调查队
They're gonna take Masarov apart piece by piece.
他们要把马萨罗维拆成碎片
Measure everything.
测量一切
Try to reverse-engineer it.
试图重新建造
Fight over ownership.
争夺所有权
I've been asked if you wanna
他们要我问你
go back out there. I said I'd ask, but...
愿不愿意参加  我答应了  但是
I've seen what I came to see.
我来的目的已经达到了
They don't stop, do they?
他们真是永不停息啊
I don't think they know how.
我想恐怕他们是不会
I told you you'd go home to Virginia without unpacking.
跟你说了你可以直接拎包回弗吉尼亚
Delta unit, move out.
三角洲小队  出发
Thank you.
谢谢